We couldn't figure out who it was. So,
how did they get their money? How did
they self-finance?
They would rob banks and post offices.
Now, remember, these were the days when
everything was done in cash, everything.
And they would just rob banks and post
offices in broad daylight.
And then, they would raid police
stations in the middle of the night,
grab the handful of cops that were on
duty, tie them up, hold them hostage,
steal all of their weapons and all of
their ammunition. And just to add insult
to injury,
there is a large military museum in
Athens, right in the center of Athens.
The Greeks are very proud of it. And in
the 1980s, somebody who was a member of
17 November went into the military
museum and realized
that none of the weapons on display had
been deactivated.
They were all live weapons
on display, rocket launchers, machine
guns. So, they went one day, a group of
four terrorists went just as the museum
opened, took everybody hostage,
and then just took all of these live
weapons off the wall.
And then a couple of months later, they
raided a military weapons depot in
Larissa in central Greece
and stole all the ammunition needed for
the weapons that they stole from the
military museum.
So, they self-financed,
they self-armed,
and then there were specialty weapons
that they
somehow came into the possession of, and
that's where I came in.
I was able to identify analytically a
connection between 17 November and
Carlos the Jackal.
And if your viewers don't know who
Carlos the Jackal was, he was the Osama
bin Laden of the 1970s and '80s. He was
the most feared terrorist on the planet.
He was a Venezuelan communist named
Ilich Ramírez Sánchez
and the media dubbed him Carlos the
Jackal.
And Carlos provided the group with the
weapons that they needed that they
couldn't steal.
I was stationed in Greece from 1998 to
2000. My entire reason for being in
Greece was to infiltrate and destroy
17 November. We promised Mrs. Welch in
1975 we would find her husband's killers
and we would bring them to justice and
we meant it. It took 27 years. I took
delivery of a level 4 armored BMW 540.
My next door neighbor was the newly
arrived British Defense Attaché, Steven
Saunders, Brigadier General one star.
I liked Steven a lot.
But he was a media [__] But he was a
media [__] Anytime he saw a camera, he
would run right in front of it and offer
up an interview and he would just loved
being on TV.
We happen to be invited to a cocktail
party
the night of the day that I took
delivery of the new car.
I was standing with Steven, with the
American Defense Attaché and the French
Defense Attaché, and Steven was making
fun of me because of my new car. As I
said, we lived next door to not next
door, but our backyards abutted. And he
says to me, "You Americans, you're so
paranoid about security." He said, "This
is an EU country. It's a NATO country.
What are you so afraid of?" And
everybody starts to chuckle.
And I said to him, "You Brits live in a
dream world. If you think that because
they have pretty beaches and palm trees
that they're not going to kill you if
they have the chance, believe me, if
they have the chance, they're going to
kill you."
And then we all laughed again. To make a
long story short, 2 weeks later, they
killed him.
They killed him in broad daylight during
the morning rush. They finally issued a
manifesto several months afterwards in
which they specifically said that they
set out that morning to kill me.
But that I was driving an armored car
and they knew that I was armed. And it
said, "And so we elected to carry out
the revolutionary sentence on the war
criminal Saunders."
That killing, everybody like Steven,
that killing
was what began to change public opinion.
17 November would attack, they killed
the Turkish ambassador, the Turkish
deputy ambassador, they killed the head
of the federal tax office, they killed
the governor of the central bank, they
killed the minister of finance, they
killed the minister of communications,
but they were largely seen as Robin
Hood, right? Oh, taxes were raised, they
set fire to six tax offices and then
murdered the head of the tax service.
And people are like, "Oh, okay, well,
they're for the poor people." No,
they're not for the poor people. It's an
armed criminal gang is all it is. So, in
2002, in April of 2002,
a man was walking in Piraeus with a
paper bag, like a grocery bag,
carrying a bomb. And he was going to put
the bomb underneath the car of a
billionaire ship owner and the bomb went
off. It blew off both of his hands and
blew out his right eye. And as he was
bleeding to death,
a policeman runs across the street,
takes off his own shirt to staunch the
blood squirting out of his stumps and
the guy confesses to being 17 November's
chief bomber. He names all the members
of 17 November and he gives the address
of the safe house where all the weapons
are stored.
And then he survived.
And so, the Greeks were able to arrest
all of them.
The three
most prominent members received
sentences of 1,765
years in prison.
The only two things that the cops were
never able to recover were the old
school typewriter that they used to type
the manifestos
and the Welch 45.
It's out there somewhere.
But anyway,
they were unusual in that
the Soviet Union was far too liberal for
them. They were old school Stalinists.
They wanted you to to fall into line or
face death.
And they saw themselves as the ones to
carry out that policy.
>> I want to ask you about Day of the
Jackal because, and this is something
that I've only recently sort of got
hipped to,
and that's because there were some
articles written recently that Candace
Owens shared that kind of tied into the
possibility of French Foreign Legion and
this kind of stuff. I don't have any
theory on that. I don't ascribe to all
of her theories, but there was an
interesting article written by a French
analyst about the possibility that there
are actual hit squads, and they might be
considered French, but they might not
actually be French. They might actually
be other Middle Eastern countries that
are actually behind some of these hits.
And I know this is different
Huh?
>> They're French.
>> Well, I don't doubt that, but
>> [laughter]
>> but what I'm saying is that
there might There are people
[clears throat] that theorize that
Israel had a role in the background of
some of these French operations, not
just banking, but also other things that
are going on in France that not many
people are very hipped to, but I wanted
to ask you about the situation with Day
of the Jackal because that story is
about de Gaulle, and I'm curious So,
you're saying that Carlos the Jackal
is the name came from that? Is that what
you're saying? That the the name
>> a funny thing. It's one of these chicken
or egg situations where
Carlos was almost caught
in a raid on his friend's apartment in
Brussels. His friend was not a terrorist
and didn't realize that Carlos
that his friend Ilich was Carlos, right?
Although he was not yet known as Carlos.
Anyway, the cops raid the apartment.
Carlos is already gone. And a French
photojournalist took pictures of like
every inch of the apartment.
And it turned out that the Belgian guy
was reading the book The Day of the
Jackal, and it was on the side table.
The French journalist just decided to
call this unnamed terrorist, we didn't
yet know it was Ilich Ramírez Sánchez,
to call him
the Jackal.
And then it just so happened that a book
that was next to The Day of the Jackal
was written by a Spanish uh I I forget
his name now, but his first name was
Carlos. And so this French reporter just
made it up out of whole cloth, Carlos
the Jackal. And then we we learned later
we learned later Carlos was like, "Where
the [__] did this name come from? I
don't like this name. Why are they
calling me Carlos? And what's this
Jackal thing? Why are they calling me
the Jackal?" I'll tell you, I met Carlos
in 2000. It took me over a year to get
permission to see him.
He's serving a life without parole
sentence in France for the murder of
seven French policemen. I had gone to
see his ex-wife, Magdalena Kopp,
in Germany. They They share a daughter.
And she she dropped out of terrorism.
She just She had had enough and she just
dropped out. She had done time in
prison. She was like, "Enough." And she
quit. So I begged her
to write to Carlos and tell him that I
really did need to talk to him. I wasn't
going to, you know, I'm I'm not trying
to get him in trouble. I only want to
know about the Greeks.
It took over a year. And then of course
yeah, the the French insisted that they
had to be there. So I go to Paris, I
meet up with the French, we take a
train. The prison was like, I don't
know, 40 minutes outside of town. And we
finally get into the prison to see
Carlos. I said, "Thank you for seeing
me. I'm John Kirakou. I'm from the CIA.
We promised Mrs. Welch that we would,
you know, find her husband's killers.
It's been 25 years.
Et cetera, et cetera.
And he he listened and he's nodding and
he's nodding and I said all I want to
know is who were the Greeks?
Just give us the names of the Greeks.
Give us one name, just someone that
would lead me to the killers.
And he goes
[__] you.
And then he just got up and walked away
from the
the you know, one of those Plexiglas
things.
He just got up and walked away and that
was the end of it. He never gave us
anything.
Two years later it didn't matter and
he's still in uh he's in prison. He'll
die in prison. He's well into his 70s
now. Utterly unrepentant, unapologetic.
This is a guy for for those of your
viewers who who don't know any of the
background. This is a guy
who kidnapped literally every oil
minister from every OPEC country
during an OPEC summit.
There was an OPEC summit taking place in
Vienna, Austria. He and his gang raided
the meeting site and they kidnapped
every member of OPEC
at the same time.
And the Saudis paid him something like a
billion dollars to let everybody go.
It was Carlos that worked with Gaddafi
to set up these training camps in Libya
where the PFLP, the PFLP-GC, the DFLP,
Abu Nidal, the IRA,
Popular Revolutionary Struggle, they all
sent their people there to be trained at
these camps in the desert. Carlos was
the money guy and Carlos was the weapons
guy. Carlos was working with the
Romanians and the Bulgarians. You know,
they were producing gigantic amounts of
weapons and ammunition and just selling
them on the gray market. It was Carlos
that had the relationship with the
Eastern Europeans to buy the AK-47s and
the hand grenades and the land mines and
the bullets and then sell them to these
groups through the Libyans.
It was all very complicated and in my
mind absolutely fascinating. You know,
minus 9/11, I would have spent the rest
of my career just working against these
groups.
>> I find it fascinating, too, because
again, it seems rare, at least in my
limited reading and research, that this
type of a person is organic or alone,
you know, weapons trafficker or whatever
terrorist person. There there's usually
networks. There's people behind them.
There's money and power. Is he just out
for his own gain or was he a true
believer in a kind of Leninist
perspective?
>> You know, for him it was a combination
of pure Marxist ideology and money.
I'm going to tell you one other story
about Carlos. I've spoken a number of
times about a guy that I used to work
with at the agency. He was a legendary
contractor named Billy Waugh.
W A U G H.
Billy was one short of the US record. He
had 17 Purple Hearts from World War II,
Korea, and Vietnam. He was a stone-cold
killer. One of these guys that would go
into a village in Vietnam and just mow
down every living thing.
So, he was a long-time CIA contractor.
He and I worked very closely together.
It was actually just the two of us in
the Middle East before 9/11. We did this
long-term operation together.
But anyway,
he told me the most fascinating story.
The details in a biography about him
that is Peace wrote
differ a little, but the core of the
story is the same. The way he told it to
me was was thusly.
He was assigned to the CIA station in
Khartoum, Sudan.
And you know, it was one of those
situations pre-9/11 where you got to
work 7 days a week, but every once in a
while, just so you don't go crazy, you
have to take a day off and sleep in.
So, there's one day he and another guy
from the station
go to the vegetable market just to buy
some vegetables.
And
he said he's there buying vegetables and
he looks over
and he sees the only other white man
that he ever saw in Khartoum. And he's
looking at this white guy in the
vegetable market and he says to his
buddy,
"That's Carlos the Jackal."
And his friend says, "Get the [__] out
of here." He said, "I'm telling you
that's Carlos the Jackal."
And then Carlos kind of got away in the
crowd. They run back to the station.
Cofer Black, who became the director of
counterterrorism and then later became
Ambassador Cofer Black and the chairman
of Blackwater after that. Cofer was the
station chief at the time and Billy says
he ran into Cofer's office. Cofer's on
an elliptical machine in the in the
office. And he says, "Cofer, I just came
from the vegetable market and I saw
Carlos the Jackal."
And Cofer says, "Get the [__] out of
here, Carlos the Jackal.
What in the world would Carlos be doing
in Sudan of all places? You're You're
You're nuts."
He said, "I'm telling you it was
Carlos."
So he says, "Well, we can't just cable
headquarters and say Carlos the Jackal's
in Khartoum. We need proof. You got to
get a picture of him."
Billy went back to the vegetable market
every single day for a month.
And then he saw him again.
So what they did is they paid these two
Sudanese guys to get into a fist fight.
And you know, in
in Africa and the Middle East, fighting
is very very rare. So two guys start
duking it out. A big circle forms around
them. Everybody wants to get a look.
And so that's what happens and Carlos,
kind of a little guy, he runs over to
get a look and he's kind of craning his
neck to see, you know, who's fighting,
what's going on and Billy's there just
going click click click click click
click click click click click click
click click.
They send the film back to headquarters
and they said, "Oh my god, it's Carlos
the Jackal." But had the presence of
mind after the fight to follow Carlos
discreetly to his house. So, they were
able to identify the house.
They initiated an operation where Carlos
was made to be unconscious temporarily.
And when Carlos woke up, he was on a
French military plane
on the way to Paris. And he's been in
prison ever since.
>> The stories are awesome. I love hearing
these kind of stories and they're not
told enough. And again, this is for the
sake of the audience and I like to see
what you think about this now reflecting
back to your younger days.
Why does the US care what
an organization of leftists are doing in
Greece? Why are you there in Greece?
>> We wouldn't have cared had they not been
murdering Americans. They killed the CIA
station chief. They killed two US
defense attaches, Bill Nordeen and
George Santis. The bomb that they used
to kill Bill Nordeen was so big
that we found Nordeen's head on the roof
of the next door neighbor's house. They
meant business. They shot and gravely
wounded the US DEA rep in the embassy.
They shot and killed a hapless Air Force
technical sergeant, an African-American
guy named Ron Stewart who was just doing
his laundry. They shot him and killed
him in the laundry room of his apartment
building. The Greek public hated that
too because he was black. They're like,
"Come on, this man's oppressed in his
own country and that's the guy that you
kill?"
So, it was because they were actively
targeting Americans
that we went after them like we did.
>> This may sound like a stupid question,
but my context for this question is not
stupidity.
If I read say Brzezinski, right?
Brzezinski and Between Two Ages. He's
got this footnote where he talks about
Professor Anthony Sutton.
And he quotes Sutton about the build-up
of the Soviet Union. And we find other
references here and there in literature
to certain figures that might have
played or attempted to play both sides
during the Cold War. We think about
Robert Maxwell. We think about an Armand
Hammer, we think about some people have
theorized Lord Victor Rothschild was not
just British intelligence but might have
also been passing intelligence to the
Soviets.
>> And on the other side, Nicolae
Ceaușescu.
>> Yeah,
there's there seems to be quite a few
instances where we're fighting this
enemy that's also aided and propped up
in many cases and perhaps the Cold War
according to say Dr. Quigley was a bit
exaggerated, right? In other words, the
memorandum that kicks off the Cold War
that Stalin is building up is it
exaggerated or is it plausible that the
Cold War is real but also at a certain
level perhaps desired?
>> Oh, I think you've hit it on the head. I
think that's exactly what the case was.
Yeah, sure. Historically here in the
United States, Jay, we've always needed
an ism to be opposed to. In the 19
teens, it was anarchism and then it was
communism and then it was socialism and
later on it became Islamism. I mean,
there's always something that we need to
rally against but at the same time,
that's how
you know, the deep state is able to
justify its budgets.
This isn't anything that's new. It's
been going on for more than a century.
Sure, you have to rally Americans
against something.
>> You know, it's like Smedley Butler said
a long time ago, war's a racket, right?
>> Oh, yeah.
>> It would seem to me as well that World
War I and World War II, although they're
obviously tragedies or serious problems
with ideologies,
but again, it's almost like there's a
dialectical
control where you want to have the
opposition to justify the existence. We
just saw this for example this week or
last week, excuse me, with the case that
they're going to put against the SPLC,
you know, sending significant amounts of
money to people heading up these
obviously fake cutout groups, the
ridiculous groups.
But also the head of the guy, you know,
the Unite the Right guy in
Charlottesville that I think many of us
thought even at the time this is kind of
a silly kind of honey trap type of
situation. And it would be really
foolish I think to be involved in that
kind of stuff and perhaps even similar
situations with J6 although I don't
think that's come up yet in the case of
the SPLC but a similar kind of template
of fomenting, hyping up, causing,
funding the opposition.
In not every case but in many cases and
that's why I think, you know, not many
people really talk about this in regard
to the Cold War that we might have had
very wealthy people in the West and
perhaps banking elites who wanted to put
money into communism, socialism and
perhaps even fascism too or into sudden
because as you said it justifies a lot
of what we do and there's a lot of
resource extraction, there's a lot of
geopolitical tactical, you know, bases
that can be set up. And you exposed by
the way, maybe I'm not right about this
but I remember years ago in the 2000s
when I was trying to really study all of
this stuff in depth. I remember seeing
all of the sudden
articles popping up maybe 2008, 9, 10,
CIA black sites exposed. They're in the
news. Suddenly we've got this place in
Romania, this black site. Right. I think
people probably thought that these
things existed but then suddenly we knew
that they did exist. And you
called a lot of that out.
>> Yeah.
>> That's why you got persecuted. Could you
explain perhaps to those that are not
familiar with your story
and I think you're a hero for what you
did. Why why why call this out? Why are
we doing this? What's the justification
from the establishment's perspective?
>> Oh, the the justification from the
establishment's perspective was that we
needed to do literally everything to
protect Americans
even if what we were doing
broke the law.
And my position was
we're either going to be a nation of
laws
or we're not.
We can't be both. You can't, you know,
Ronald Reagan called the United States a
shining city on a hill.
A beacon of hope for human rights and
civil rights and civil liberties.
I want that to be true.
And so you can't be that shining city on
a hill
and have a torture program and a secret
prison program and an illegal rendition
program and torture people to death and
then just dig a ditch next to the
torture chamber and dump their body in
the ditch and then talk about how you
support human rights.
So we're going to have to either pick
one or the other.
And I came down on the side of law and
order. I mean I
hate to sound like an idealogue but I
came down on the side of
you know, the rule of law.
There was a I blew the whistle on the
CIA's torture program in December of
2007.
And I said three things. I said the CIA
was torturing its prisoners, that
torture was official US government
policy and that the policy had been
personally approved by the president.
And I was prosecuted for that. I wish
that I had blown the whistle on the
secret prison program. There was a woman
She was a contemporary of mine at the
agency and I I respected her deeply.
She swears that she was not the one who
blew the whistle, so I won't use her
name.
But she was working at the White House
right after right around the time I got
arrested and she was escorted out of the
White House by the Secret Service and
they took her badge and told her never
to come back and then she was forcibly
retired from the CIA.
They said they leaked that she had blown
the whistle on the Well, they didn't say
blow the whistle, that she had leaked
information about the existence of the
secret prisons.
She swore that it wasn't her. And in in
private conversations, she swore to me
that it wasn't her.
And I said, "Well, if it was you, then
you are one of the great heroes of the
early part of the 21st century."
And she swore it wasn't her, but
I I don't know. I was just one of those
guys that believed that we were the good
guys. And if we are the good guys then
we have to act like the good guys. If
you want to be for torture
you can be for torture but you have to
change the law. You can't just pretend
that the law doesn't exist or that
because you're the good guy it doesn't
exist for you
that nobody else can torture but you
can.
And so I said no, enough is enough and I
said something.
>> I've heard you and many others
and I think it was you but I don't want
to misquote you if it wasn't you but
this is often said that you know, when
people say, well, what what is
espionage? What are we doing in all
these other countries? The answer is
usually given something like we are
doing illegal activities in other
countries legally or something like
that.
>> Yeah.
>> How do you balance as you're say
being trained and going into this world
the idea on the one hand that
there's all these legalities which which
you mentioned quite often in interviews.
You mentioned for example with Tucker
that you know, certain people in the
agency couldn't have public support for
this or that candidate, Bob Dole or
whoever.
>> Right.
>> Uh but at the same time we've got this
situation where we've got to go in other
countries and do illegal things under
the cover of legality.
>> Mhm.
>> How do you balance that as you're going
through that and then make the sort of
conscious decision to say, well, in this
case now the torture program is I'm not
defending it. I'm just saying like I'm
curious as to your process as you're
working through these issues.
>> You go into a job like that really
believing that you're the good guys.
You really believe it and you understand
from your very first day that your job
is to break the laws of foreign
countries.
Not to break the laws of the United
States. That is forbidden.
I remember one of my early bosses
telling me
don't ever lie to finance, medical or
security. They can ruin your life.
Don't ever lie to a judge.
And he said, and don't ever lie to me.
Everybody else you can lie to.
Everybody's lying all day long. You know
the the old cliche, how do you know when
a CIA officer is lying? His lips are
moving.
So,
yeah, I I believed that. You know, we go
overseas and we lie, we commit
espionage, we convince other people to
commit espionage or to commit treason
for us because we're the good guys.
But then,
when we're violating the Federal Torture
Act of 1946,
when we're violating the United Nations
Convention Against Torture, which we
which we wrote,
and has the force of law because it was
ratified by the United States Senate,
nobody ever said we could violate the
law in the United States.
You know, if I go overseas, I'm I'm
going to use 1949
as as an example. If I go overseas and I
receive a cable saying, "Hey, listen,
the polls say that the communists are
going to win the Italian election. So,
steal the election for the
conservatives." I'd say, "Okay."
And then I spend $150,000 recruiting
journalists and and planting stories and
then, what do you know, the communists
lose.
Well, I I would sleep very well that
night because I'm the good guy and the
communists are the bad guys and so I did
what my job is. But if the order is to
overthrow the American government or to
influence an American election or
or
torture someone in violation of American
law,
absolutely never.
Never.
Because then we're not the good guys
anymore.
Like did we learn nothing over the
course of all these decades? Did we
learn nothing from Watergate, for
example? Nothing from Iran-Contra.
So, you got to put your foot down.
>> You know, you often hear from
establishment types when this topic is
brought up, "Well, if we don't, they
will. I remember reading
I remember reading decades ago or excuse
me a book written decades ago. I think
it was a John Marks's book about the
Manchurian Candidate and MK Ultra. And
the argument was made at that time, if
we do not engage in these testing
experimentation projects, the Soviets
will. If we don't do this, they will. Do
you find that to be a flimsy
justification and why?
>> Yeah, that's flimsy. Oh my god, where
should we even start with MK Ultra and
and the sub
the sub operations of MK Ultra, MK
Chickwit and MK what whatever it was
called Night Writer or whatever it was
called, I can't remember. There were
like six of them.
Imagine
being in a meeting at the CIA and say,
"Listen, there's this scientist in
Switzerland and he just developed this
thing called LSD
and it does crazy [__]
And we've heard that the Russians are
developing expertise in mind control and
ESP and what they called remote viewing
and all this silliness that never came
to pass. So, we got to do the same thing
cuz the Russians are doing it. In fact,
the Russians weren't doing it. The
Chinese were doing it.
But we didn't have sources in China at
the time.
So,
you're in this meeting and a
determination is made that yes, we're
going to do this. We're going to call it
MK Ultra.
And what we're going to do is we're
going to experiment on American citizens
and we're never going to tell them we're
experimenting on them. Better yet, let's
start by experimenting on our own
employees.
And so, they start dosing their own CIA
employees with LSD. People are jumping
out of windows and off of balconies and
they're like, "Ah, no, we shouldn't do
it on our own people. Let's just do it
in let's say San Francisco."
And then they go to San Francisco and
they did a whole bunch of horrible
illegal [__] in San Francisco.
Things like
they recruited an army of prostitutes.
And they set up a safe house in San
Francisco. And they said, "Go out and
pick up a date, bring him back to the
safe house. We're going to dose him with
LSD, and then we're going to see if
he'll give us his most deeply held
secrets
under the LSD."
All it did was it just made people
crazy.
Then they said, "You know what? Maybe we
should do something different. We should
develop a germ.
Let's develop a germ, and we'll just
release it into the air, and see if it
makes people sick."
So, they developed this this germ.
They waited until an unusually foggy day
in San Francisco.
And then they just drive around town
in these pickup trucks
with pipes releasing the germ into the
fog.
They knew it was successful
when a week later 11 people had gone to
hospital emergency rooms with this
really rare upper respiratory infection.
That we caused.
Then they decided
what it would be like they wanted to
know what it would be like if they could
make like everybody in a town crazy.
And so,
they put LSD
in the flour
that was supplied to the only bakery in
a little village in France. The baker
who had no idea that the that the flour
was full of LSD made bread that day like
he did every day.
Sold the bread to everybody in the
village. Everybody in the village went
nuts. There's even a Wikipedia page
about this.
That's the CIA. All of that was illegal.
Now, this was also very very secret, top
secret until 1975.
The Church Committee on Capitol Hill
the Church Committee on the Senate side
and the Pike Committee on the House side
developed this information and they
called the CIA's leadership to come and
testify under oath in public hearings.
MK Ultra was outed and the Director of
Central Intelligence, Dick Helms,
Richard Helms, was specifically told by
Senator Church, "Don't destroy the
documents."
He went back to the agency and told
them, "Destroy all the documents."
They destroyed 85% of the documents on
MK Ultra. So, what we know today about
MK Ultra comes from the 15% of the
documents that survived the
giant, you know, destruction.
And that's why we don't have answers to
so many of these questions.
Dick Helms was held in contempt of
Congress. He was fined a few hundred
dollars.
And then when he got back to the agency
after having taken a plea
and having been fined,
there was a parade of CIA employees
standing in the hallway
leading to his office.
Each one throwing in cash into a hat to
pay his fine.
They all looked out for each other.
>> Yeah, it seems like I mean, I don't want
to say a strictly speaking a cult, but
some people have written about it as if
it's the quote cult of intelligence.
Like that's the Victor Marchetti book.
The idea being then that, you know,
you're sort of bound to almost like a
kind of a quasi secret society perhaps.
Maybe that's an exaggeration, but
>> Same idea.
>> Yeah.
>> No, you're right. It's the same idea.
>> Briefly little detour here cuz I want to
I've not heard you. You probably have
commented, I just haven't heard it yet.
You know, lately the government is is
seeming to give a nod at many levels to
so-called aliens and UFOs. I personally
do not believe in aliens, but we do have
a lot of bizarre stories and instances
and and advanced technology that seems
to perhaps mirror or mimic some of these
UFO phenomena. I'm curious of what you
think about that because when I hear
about aliens and UFOs and these stories,
there could be something spiritual going
on for sure, but it also reminds me of
what happens if you have a bad LSD trip.
>> Yeah.
>> I and and on that topic of MK Ultra, it
makes me wonder if you know, there
couldn't be and I think there's
definitely a you know, a
deep state components to the UFO alien
phenomenon. But also specifically in the
descriptions of what people go through
and how they describe these experiences,
do you think that there's any likelihood
that this is sort of a propagated
intentional perhaps mythology or idea
that's being seeded or planted that
we're now under some sort of a you know,
alien attack. Maybe you think that the
phenomenon is real. I don't know your
view. Could there be an MK Ultra, I know
it's defunct, but something akin to that
that overlaps with the UFO alien
phenomenon?
>> Oh, it's absolutely possible. You know,
I I I have to admit I'm of two minds on
this issue.
On the one hand, I long believed that
these sightings that people have are
largely explainable.
And when they're not explainable,
there's I think a likelihood that it's
some kind of experimental technology.
You know, DARPA is working 20 years
ahead of everybody else and
it's probably some top secret, you know,
thing.
On my very first day at the CIA, I had
lunch with my new boss.
And I said half jokingly, "So, where are
the aliens?"
And he laughed and he said, "That is
the first question that every single one
of us has on his first day."
And I said, "So, what's the answer?"
And he said, "We don't do any of that
stuff. It's all at the Pentagon." He
said, "I have no idea what they are,
where they are. Nobody here does. It's
all at the Pentagon."
With that said,
I've told this story before, but I'll
repeat it.
When I was in high school, my mom and
dad bought a restaurant
in Sharon, Pennsylvania. We lived in New
Castle, Pennsylvania.
So, they're about 15 mi apart. And to go
from New Castle to Sharon, you have to
go through Amish country. And the Amish
don't use electricity. So, it's very,
very dark. One Friday night, my dad and
I left the house because we were working
midnight shift. We always work midnight
shift on Fridays and Saturdays.
We're driving through Amish country, and
there is this brilliant, like blinding
flash of white light. And then there's a
second flash, and then a third flash.
And we're both looking up at this thing,
like, "What is that?"
And then this orange trapezoid
lights up. And it's just hovering about
1,500 ft off the ground in the shape of,
I hate to say it, in the shape of a
saucer.
And I said, "What is that?" My dad pulls
the car over. We get out of the car.
We're standing there staring at this
thing.
A guy pulls up behind us, gets out of
his car, and he goes, "What is that?"
And my dad said, "I don't know." And
then it goes
at this fantastic speed that just defies
defied
the laws of physics.
Never made any sound.
We stood there for at least another 30
seconds thinking, "Is it going to come
back or what?" I don't know.
So, we get back in the car.
And I said to him,
mind you, I was 17 at the time, so I
didn't know any better. I said, "So,
should we like call somebody? Should we
call the cops or something?"
And he said,
"And say what?
We saw a flying saucer and it flew
away?"
He said, "People are going to think
we're insane."
And so, the only person I I told was my
mom the next day.
Well, years later, I not years later,
couple of years later,
I come to school here in Washington. I
had a cousin who was an F-15 pilot.
And um I always looked up to him cuz he
was older than me and you know, he's a
pilot and he's so cool.
I said to him,
"Hey listen, my dad and I saw this crazy
thing once a couple of years ago." and I
told him.
And he said, "Oh listen." He said,
"Every one of us at the Air Force"
He said, "We all see [__] like that all
the time. And sometimes they come up out
of the water off the coast of Norfolk."
I said, "What are they?" He said, "I
don't know." He said, "But they very
well could be ours."
It's just that he said, "I'm not cleared
to know what it is. I don't know what
the heck it is." I said, "Well, what do
you do when you see something like
that?" He said, "We fill out a form. We
send it to the Pentagon and nobody ever
hears about it again."
So I I don't know. I I I've never seen,
you know, little green men or anything
like that. I I
I I wonder too if on the one hand
I I lean in the direction of some kind
of futuristic advanced technology,
right? That's being experimented with.
On the other hand, I wonder
if
let's say it is something
extraterrestrial.
The government all these years hasn't
wanted to panic us.
Okay, well guess what? Now all this
video's been leaked from the Pentagon
over the last 5 years and nobody cares
and there hasn't been any panic. So why
not just come out with it now and tell
us what it is?
>> I feel very similarly about that topic.
I do want to shift gears a little bit
because there's so many hot topics I do
want your take on. A lot of them are
unfortunately, I know this is selfish,
but kind of my pet thoughts and that's
why I want to bounce my my theories and
my thoughts off of you. Gordon Thomas
wrote a fascinating book about Mossad
called Gideon's Spies many years ago,
who's a journalist and there's several
chapters that related to the Vatican and
the Cold War. Particularly the chapter
on John Paul II was interesting because
there were significant advancements that
Israel was able to achieve in terms of
recognition and influence through John
Paul II on record. I don't think that's
any anything too controversial.
>> Right.
>> He discussed, for example, the Vatican
becoming hip to the Mossad wanting to
and trying to bug the Vatican.
Then I noticed, if you look at the
dates, not too long after that, John
Paul II did recognize the nation-state
of Israel as a political entity, which
the Vatican had not done for many
decades.
And that to me is a window into the
possibility of a backdoor connection or
influence there that might be pretty
significant geopolitically speaking,
because you do have the Roman Catholic
Church taking some pretty significant
advances in terms of changing their
attitudes towards the nation-state of
Israel and regarding Judaism in the last
several decades post-Vatican II. I'm
curious
to what degree do you think that is a
window into a influence campaign? Is it
significant? Do you think that's
plausible? And there also seem to be
significant admissions in that book and
other books as well with related to
Gladio, that the CIA had a really close
connection, perhaps even more than a
connection, perhaps
people on the hook to what the CIA
wanted throughout the Cold War in
regards to the Vatican?
>> Yeah.
>> Was that a trap to basically sort of
have soft power influence through the
Vatican?
>> Yeah.
That was always my understanding, yes.
There were old-timers at the agency when
I first joined who took credit for
making John Paul II Pope.
>> That's what I've heard, yeah.
>> Yeah, this was a political decision from
the very beginning.
It was done to weaken the Soviet Union.
They knew that having a Pope from
Poland, which was a Soviet satellite
state at the time,
would reap untold benefits because it
would distract the Soviets. And then at
exactly the same time, the Solidarity
movement took root in the beginning in
the Gdansk Shipyard in Poland. And so,
there was no downside for the West to
John Paul being Pope. If anything, this
was like a gift.
And the recognition of Israel, I
remember how controversial that was at
the time. That was just like an extra
added freebie
that we got on top of everything that we
got with the Soviets.
So, yeah, I think that was the case.
>> I remember, you know, a lot of the texts
will point to, you know, a pretty close
relationship with Henry Kissinger
>> Yes.
>> even going back to Paul the VI having a
very close relationship there as well as
William Casey. I think in the you had
this period where there were pretty
hardcore traditional Catholic people in
the CIA like Casey and others known as
Templars that were very committed to
that alliance. And I suspect and I
wonder, I know that has opposed Trump in
recent months.
And then there was this meeting where
Cardinal Christoph back in January was
at the White House and there was these
tense words supposedly said and there's
this story that they reminded Cardinal
Christoph and Leo of the Avignon papacy
and the power that the state can have.
And I'm just to me, I just thought that
was a fascinating window into perhaps
what's going on with
not just the deep state, but the deep
church and perhaps an influence in in
that structure.
>> And you know, there was a book published
recently in the last, I'm going to say
year or two, and I I apologize that I
don't remember the title, talking about
the joint CIA Vatican operation to
publish Doctor Zhivago and to
>> I heard you say this. Yeah, I heard you
say this. Yeah, I didn't even know this.
I heard you say this.
>> Yeah, make it available to Soviet
citizens at the International Book Fair
in Brussels in like 1971
or whatever whatever it was. Where you
had even the KGB minders who had
accompanied this delegation of Soviet
citizens to the International Book Fair
themselves were bringing copies of
Doctor Zhivago back to the Soviet Union.
It's funny, it was a book that that
nobody really paid any attention to
until the Cold War got really hot. And
then somebody at the CIA said, "We've
got to smuggle this into the Soviet
Union." Well, how do you do that?
Well, we could do it by asking the
Vatican
to do it for us.
You know? so the Russians were all over
the American book tent at the
international book fair not paying any
attention at all to the Vatican book
tent and every time a Soviet citizen
would come to the Vatican tent they'd
say, "Hey, you want to go in the back
room? There's a back room. You're going
to want to go back there." And then they
had all these copies of Doctor Zhivago
in Russian.
It got to the point where people would
would tear out like 10 pages at a time
and just tape them around their legs and
then just you know, re-enter the Soviet
Union with a book taped around their
legs 10 pages at a time, collate the
pages again
and then pass it around to their
friends.
>> I think I have an idea as to why and for
those who don't know I did write a book
and two other books after that esoteric
Hollywood which largely deals with
propaganda in films and in Hollywood and
in fiction. But for those that might not
know in the audience and you've talked
about this in many interviews John which
is the interest that the CIA and other
entities Pentagon even military they
have in Hollywood and fiction. Why would
the the CIA care about Doctor Zhivago?
What what is that going to do in the
Soviet Union? Who cares about that? Why
would they do that?
>> Yeah,
it's it's funny. You declare victory in
small increments.
Right? And so if you are able to get a
book like Doctor Zhivago into the hands
of a Soviet citizen
and maybe make one Soviet citizen
question his or her own government
that's a successful operation.
You plan small and hope for the best
and that's really what it was all about.
>> There's a movie I know you're very
familiar with Three Days of the Condor.
>> Yeah, it's
>> And you've got Robert Redford sitting in
this you know, bookstore and he's
basically just reading books and looking
for things all day long. Is that real or
is that exaggerated?
>> No, that's real.
That's real. When when I first joined
the agency that was called active
measures.
Yeah, it it's it's all about the
propaganda and it's all about combating
propaganda. Um, it it's a 24-hour a day,
7-day a week process.
>> In films, something like The Americans,
and we see back during the Cold War,
number stations are putting out the
message codes to the Soviet operatives
in the US. If I recall, it's been some
years since I watched Three Days of the
Condor, but Robert Redford's like
scanning for propaganda, but isn't it
also perhaps like messages from
Soviet operatives to certain cells or
something like he's trying to see if he
can find something I maybe it's not, I
don't remember. Does that still go on in
terms of I know there's number stations
sort of putting out those codes and
whatnot. Um, is that still happening at
that type of a level? Okay.
>> Oh, yeah. As recently as a week ago, I
was just I I I just did a podcast
episode of my own where I talked to two
former CIA colleagues. One was a CIA
attorney and the other was a anti-Soviet
operations officer. And we were talking
about that. And I said, you know,
when I was 9 years old,
I've said this before. When I was 9
years old, I told my parents I wanted to
be a spy when I grew up.
And um they bought me walkie-talkies and
disappearing ink and stuff like that for
Christmas. When I was 16, I told them I
wanted to be a spy in the Middle East.
And I I meant it. And I became a spy in
the Middle East. Well, my dad, when I
was 9, my dad took me to an auction at
one of these local farms. We we lived in
a very rural area.
And at the end of the auction, all the
junk that didn't sell, they just threw
into one box, and my dad got the box for
50 cents. And it included a shortwave
radio.
So, that night,
we put some batteries in this thing, and
I listened to an AM station. It was WGN
in Chicago. And I remember thinking,
"Wow, I'm in Newcastle, Pennsylvania,
and I can hear a station in Chicago?"
Cuz you know, when the sun goes down, AM
stations go on augmented power, and if
you're a 50,000 W station, you can be
picked up
as much as like 1,500 miles away. So, I
was getting Chicago and New York and
Boston and Atlanta and Dallas a couple a
couple times.
The next night, I switched it to
shortwave. Just to see if I can get this
this on AM, what about the shortwave?
And I got BBC and Radio Moscow and Radio
Havana and all different kinds of of
things. Well, one of the things that I
heard that night and many many nights
after that
was just a man's voice
saying
eight
three
six for hours. And I'm like, what is
this? What What it is, it's a spy
What he's doing is called reading from a
one-time pad.
So, he's reading an encrypted message by
giving only the numbers associated with
the letters
that are encrypted.
So, those numbers will change with every
message. So, I mentioned this on the
podcast the other day and the the other
case officer he said, "Oh, listen." He
said, "I still listen to shortwave and I
can tell you that a week ago
I heard a guy reciting one-time pad
numbers."
So, there there it's some Russian spy
somewhere in the United States and he's
reading it from his one-time pad.
>> There was a number station down in Miami
that's like near Cuba that's still
spitting out numbers codes. I'm not sure
if the British have these as well. Um
so, I'll go ahead and start reading the
super chats. HushTone says, "Jay, you
look like clavicular you're jayvicular."
Good one. Albert Smith, $5. Jay, you've
got another sad hair day. Well, I didn't
want to look too silly uh talking to
John Kiriakou, so I just went with I
don't know Rob Thomas from Matchbox 20
mixed with James Bond. So, Ralph thanks
$10. Jay, you're researching topics but
you're muted. Okay, we unmuted. Reckon
$5. Bro, in case you didn't know you're
live. I know. JayML, $15.
Why are so many ex-CIA in US politics?
And what about the Democratic Party say
Governor Virginia? Can we trust any of
these people, John?
>> No.
We can't trust them.
>> answer. [laughter]
>> No. I I'll tell you
I was I was the mentor to a guy Will
Hurd. Will is an was an awesome case
officer, as honest as the day is long.
Our politics were different, but I I
loved the guy. And he told us one day he
said, "Listen, I'm going to resign." I
was like, "What?" I said, "Will, you're
a natural-born case officer. Why would
you resign?" He says, "I want to run for
Congress."
I said, "Run for Congress, buddy." I
said, "That's that's not a step up.
It's not."
Well, he he resigned and he ran for
Congress and he won. Here's a guy who's
half black, half white and he wins three
times in a Supreme Court-mandated
majority Hispanic district. That's how
honest and popular he was. And then he
decided it's all posturing, no real work
gets done. I'm going to quit and run for
president. He runs for president for
about 15 minutes a year two years ago.
He dropped out before the primaries even
began. And the last I heard he was on
the board of directors at OpenAI making
millions and millions and millions of
dollars. So it worked out for him. But
you know, people like Elissa Slotkin and
and Abby Spanberger, it's all about the
power. Listen, Abby, even at the agency
Abby
Abby was known as somebody who wasn't
going to be around long because she
needed she needed time to win election
to different offices so that she could
run for president. That's what it's all
about. Elissa Slotkin's exactly the same
way.
The idea is that automatically they're
both attractive candidates for vice
president.
And then the next time when it's their
turn,
they run for president. It's all about
power.
>> That leads me to the last question I had
for you on my list here as we kind of
wind down with the super chats.
And that is we cover quite a bit on my
channel, the idea of high-level steering
committees, foundations, NGOs, think
tanks. They seem to have a lot of power.
>> Yeah.
>> Americans look at the president, they
look at the, you know, Congress, they
look at the the Senate, you know,
Supreme Court. And certainly those
entities have power. But it seems like
the there's certain agendas that never
change with the politicians that come
and go. For example, our foreign policy
seems to be dictated by Israel for many,
many decades.
>> Yes.
>> Um what is the real
level of power, you could say, for these
types of supra-governmental
entities, these steering committees,
CFR, trilateral, or AIPAC, you know, as
a lobby group, or perhaps beyond that,
something beyond AIPAC, a mega group,
something like that. What's the real
power structure, John?
>> Oh, they're all part of what we are now
calling the deep state, all of them.
CFR is a great example.
Bilderberg is another. I I um
Someone to whom I was once very close,
I'll put it that way,
found herself in a position where she
began attending these meetings.
And I said, "You got to tell me, what
what goes on in these meetings? What are
they talking about? Are they like, you
know, manipulating global markets and,
you know, foreign policies and stuff?"
And she said, "It's all about weapon
sales."
All of these meetings, whether it's
Shangri-La or Bilderberg or any of them,
it's all about weapon sales. Yes, the
Bill Clintons and the Bill Gates of the
world and and the, you know,
prime ministers of this country and that
country, they're all talking about the
big overarching global issues and
economies and stuff like that. Yes, but
at the end of the day, it all comes down
to which defense contractor made what
deal
at every one of these conferences.
>> Well, that would also still overlap with
tech because we we heard this
>> Absolutely.
>> We we heard this last uh Bilderberg
meeting on a couple weeks ago. What
dominated the supposed talking points
were CBDCs, AI. It seems like Bilderberg
in the last 10 years has has really
allegedly focused on a whole lot of tech
stuff. Is that Is that fit in with that?
>> Absolutely, yes. Right now it's all
about tech and I think it will be even
more so in the in the future. Yeah, it's
all about tech.
>> Container of $15. Jay, what does John I
know he did mention this earlier. What
does John think about SRI and CIA
programs studying remote viewing?
>> For the CIA, remote viewing was a
failure. They could never figure it out.
They could never make it work. It was
always my understanding the Russians
also failed.
The Chinese failed. I think it's just
not possible. I think it's not a thing.
>> Harsh says for $10. John, could you tell
us what you think about Elpidophoros?
There was a discussion of a phone call.
I can't remember the original video.
What did you think of that?
>> Uh see, now you're going to put me on
the spot here.
>> Maybe. I don't know. You know, if you if
you want to don't want to say you don't
have to say.
>> Elpidophoros is the Archbishop of the
Greek Orthodox Church in America.
He is widely believed
to be
by far the leading candidate to be the
next Ecumenical Patriarch of
Constantinople.
He's young. He's 58 years old.
He's good-looking.
He's widely respected.
He has not been kind to me personally.
Maybe I should leave it at that.
>> Fair enough. Hendrick says, "Olof Palme
of the Swedish Prime Minister He's a
Swedish Prime Minister in the 1980s
>> Was assassinated.
>> was uh yeah, assassinated probably by a
Gladio cell.
There was a a CIA operation called Red
Socks where they had Johnny Mustache Men
followers in the Ukraine. And this was
part of the Maidan coup." Interesting, I
had not heard that. He's saying that
there's a cell that is similar to that
group that was He's saying is a Gladio
cell that in the Ukraine was called Red
Socks, which helped with the Maidan coup
is what he's saying.
>> Huh.
I have no idea. I always heard that
Palma was killed by a Kurd.
He ended up being convicted and then and
then
on appeal the conviction was overturned.
He was released and they never
conclusively solved that murder.
>> But Mountain Walk $10 J, ask John does
he glow in the dark? Well, he's a
whistleblower, so if that's what you're
referring to.
>> This is not a formal announcement yet,
but we are winding down my deep focus
podcast and we're going to start a new
in 2 weeks
on YouTube under Real John Kiriakou.
It's going to be called John Kiriakou's
Briefing Room.
>> That'll be a different channel or the
same channel redone?
>> It's going to have to be a different
channel, I'm sorry to say.
>> Okay.
>> And J, when you came on my show, we went
for an hour and a half talking about
mostly about Orthodox theology and
threats to
to Orthodoxy. It was fascinating. I
couldn't believe 90 minutes had passed
and and they turned it into three
separate episodes. It was wonderful.
>> Perfect. Yeah, that's great and that is
going to be on the deep focus or is it
going to be on your new channel? What is
that going to
>> to be on the new channel.
>> Okay, awesome. Let's see. Porphyry says
there's a secret Asian peptide. Okay.
These are some really weird questions,
though. Here come all the schizos. I'm
joking. Uh Jude says for $5, to clarify
my last question, I want to know can
John talk about what was going on in his
time in the Middle East? That's a broad
question.
>> Lots was going on in the Middle East. On
the one hand, you had the Arab-Israeli
peace process, which we believed at the
time was really taking hold. And when I
was stationed in Bahrain, we actually
sponsored the Arab-Israeli peace talks
on the environment and then I went to
Oman for the Arab-Israeli peace talks on
water.
I mean, it was weird to see like Israeli
flags flying in Bahrain and Israeli
diplomats walking around crazy. At the
same time though,
the first Intifada began while I was in
Bahrain and got pretty ugly, like really
ugly. I mean, people died, others were
executed. It was nasty. I I went into
Kuwait City with the Marines on
Liberation Day back in '91 and then, you
know, 9/11 and
it was kind of crazy.
>> Josh says, "Thank you both. John, have
you noticed any patterns from CIA or FBI
drawing from recruiting Mormons or
perhaps or other cult groups like
Quakers, Jehovah's Witnesses, or
Scientologists?"
>> Oh, yeah, yeah. I never encountered a
Scientologist, but Mormons are very,
very overly represented in both the CIA
and the FBI to a very slightly lesser
extent in NSA. And the reason is simple.
Number one, they've never done anything.
They don't swear, they don't drink, they
don't smoke, they don't gamble, they
don't screw around, they don't do
anything. They don't even eat chocolate.
And so, they just blow right through the
polygraph exam.
More importantly,
is most of them go on these missions
when they're 18 or 19 years old and they
go to Brigham Young, to the mission
center, and they learn how to speak
these funky languages that nobody else
speaks. Uzbek, Tajik, Pashtu, these
African languages. And so, they arrive
on the job already fluent in these
languages and they can be sent
operationally immediately overseas. So,
the agency and the bureau just love
Mormons.
>> Yeah, absolutely. By the way, that's a
vindication of something that people
will keep challenging me on when I
mention that. Jude says for $10, "What I
was specifically asking John about with
the Middle East earlier, I'm sorry, I
couldn't find your other super chat."
You said, "What did John think was going
on, for example, in the Antiochian
Church during his time in the Middle
East?"
>> I attended the Antiochian Church when I
was stationed in the Middle East, just
because there was no Greek Orthodox
church,
specifically in Kuwait, the Antiochians
were very strong.
You know, I don't remember there being
any controversy when I was living there
in the '90s. It was all pretty
straightforward. And then, when I was
stationed in Bahrain, I was very close
friends with the Greek Consul General.
She was a Greek-American.
There was no Cypriot representation
there, so she covered Cyprus as well.
And then she said to me one day, "Hey,
Archbishop Christodoulos is going to
come to Bahrain, and he wants to meet
with the Emir. We're going to have all
of the Orthodox, the Greeks and the
Cypriots, go with him to see the Emir."
The Emir was surprised to see me. He had
no idea. I mean, there was no reason why
he would have known that I was Orthodox.
We had the meeting, and then he pulls me
aside,
>> [laughter]
>> and he says to me, he whispers,
"I like your Ayatollah." He said, "I
like your Imam. I trust him." And I
said, "He likes you, Your Highness."
Next thing you know, the Emir donates a
giant plot of land. It was like 2 acres.
And we built the first ever Orthodox
church in Bahrain. It was very very
generous. In Kuwait, there were already
Orthodox churches. Later on, toward the
end of the '90s, they built an
Antiochian church in Doha.
I was in Dubai a few weeks ago,
and there are churches in both Dubai and
Abu Dhabi.
I don't think there's anything in
Muscat, and absolutely absolutely
positively nothing in Saudi Arabia
anywhere. You'll lose your head.
Um but things were going pretty well for
the Antiochians when I was living there.
>> Hanner says, "Have you guys read Which
Path to Persia from 2009 Brookings
Institute?" Yes, I've I've read the
whole thing. I'm familiar with it. I did
actually look it up the other day. In
it, they admit that the US will go to
war for Israel and Iran. The US is not
getting bombed by Iran, but the Gulf
allies are. I assume John probably
agrees with that.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Absolutely.
>> John, are there other members of N17
that perhaps never got caught and
continue in Greek leftist parties.
>> Yes. There was one in particular who
admitted that he was one of the two
shooters in the Welch assassination. He
dropped out of 17 November. He was the
only one to voluntarily leave and joined
the Greek Communist Party and became the
president of Greece's largest labor
union.
Greece is one of those rare countries
which very stupidly has a statute of
limitations on murder.
And so he was never prosecuted. He got
away scot-free with the Welch
assassination.
>> Banana says for $20, "John, can you talk
about the CIA culture and its influence
in America, for example, in
universities, Middle Eastern countries,
and spreading Americanism in terms of
soft power?"
>> Wow. We we would need a whole episode
for that.
The answer obviously is you're exactly
right. That CIA soft power is being
exerted everywhere that you've just
cited, whether it's in television series
or Hollywood movies or the media or
across universities. You know, I was
recruited by my grad school professor
and then with passage of the 1993 Equal
Employment Opportunity Act, that became
illegal. So what they did is they just
went around the EEOC. What they do now
is if you are within 3 years of
retirement and you're a senior
operations officer,
they'll send you back to your alma mater
to teach some innocuous course. A buddy
of mine right now is teaching a course
at Indiana University called
Espionage in Soviet Literature.
Nobody gives a [__] about Espionage in
Soviet Literature. The whole point of
the class is for people to come up to
him after class and say, "Hey, I'd
really like to join the CIA." And then
he says, "Let me introduce you to a
friend of mine."
That's what it's for.
>> This is from Penny for $20. Is House of
Cards worth watching or what are the TV
shows or movies that really give
insights into accuracy with the CIA.
>> House of Cards definitely is worth
watching. That is the story of the
Clinton family.
I mean, they don't even try to mask it.
House of Cards is about the Clintons.
Yes.
Don't miss it. But an even better show
is The Americans. A former colleague of
mine in the CIA's Counterterrorism
Center, Joe Weisberg,
resigned.
I remember the day he resigned. He He
came up to me, he said, "Buddy, I just
resigned." I was like, "What? Why would
you resign?" And he said, "This job is
just not for me. I said, "I don't have
it in my gut to convince somebody to
commit
treason." He said, "I just can't do it."
But he was unmarried, no kids. I said,
"What are you going to do?" He said,
"I'm going to go to Hollywood and find
my fortune."
And he he published a very highly
regarded novel that was heavily redacted
because it was so true to life.
And then immediately created The
Americans.
And never has to work again a day in his
life.
>> Yeah, it's great show. It's my favorite
one of my favorite TV shows, definitely.
We We've done several podcasts with our
good buddy Mark S.
Russian analyst, specialist, translator,
translates KGB stuff. And of course, he
did a great podcast with me on The
Americans. Everybody be sure and follow
John Kiriakou. John, thank you so much.
I'm honored to speak with you and so so
so proud of your work and what you're
doing and seeing you all over all these
podcasts. And great episode on Tucker,
by the way.
>> Thank you very very much. Appreciate it.
It's good to see you again.